Name: Nyein Chan Aung

Position: Digital Product & Project Professional

Address: Yangon, Myanmar

Phone: 091212121



My name is Nyein Chan Aung. I was born in 7th Aug, 1990. I'm currently working as a Product Manager at Village Link, one of the subsidiaries of Myanma Awba. I am mainly responsible for product management, UI/UX research, user analysis, QA testing, and the product launch of our company's many products. I am leading the development of a delivery social agricultural platform with registered farmers. My ability to understand the system and database design allowed me to migrate the hundred thousand user-generated datasets from the legacy system to a completely new platform in 2021.

I started my career in the tech industry as a developer while I was studying Business Information Technology. After that, I moved forward into product development and management when I found my enthusiasm for the art of product development lifecycle applying Agile Methodology. However, I am still actively sharing the technical workload by reviewing the source code for quality assurance and taking responsibility for the server deployment using different cloud service providers such as AWS, Microsoft Azure, and Digital Ocean.

I have experience organizing hackathons a few years back from now, before the pandemic. We also initiated the UniHackChallenge hackathon series that focused on university students applying their skills from the classroom to real-world problems. I contributed as a mentor such as The Hackathon 2018 and 2019 organized by Ooredoo Myanmar, AngelHack Hackathon Myanmar 2018.

Moreover, I participated in several hackathons related to my career. Along the journey, I was awarded the second prize in the YIC AG-Hack Hackathon, which was designed to ideate solutions that support the Agri-sector, organized by Seedstars, powered by Myanma Awba in Jun 2019. Our team developed a mobile application, that can guide how to use Agri-input products, with augmented reality technology. As my second achievement, after I joined my current organization, we participated in the I2N challenge program which aimed at identifying innovative solutions for nutritious food. We won the second prize by presenting the product idea of matchmaking for Buyers and Sellers in the farming product market.

SUMMARY

Dedicated and passionate product expert with 8+ years of experience in various technical industries (education, finance, agriculture). My major objective is to contribute to the business by utilizing my technical and business management skillset. I am eager to improve my experience and knowledge in delivering qualified digital products that provide value to clients and users.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence (Msc in DSAI)

- Asian Institute of Technology (2024-Currnet)

Business Information Technology (BSc Hons)

University of Greenwich (2011 - 2014)

Bachelor of Laws (LL. B)

Yangon University of Distance Education, Yangon, Myanmar (2007 - 2010)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Manager

Village Link Co. Ltd.

Nov 2019 to Present

Job Responsibility

- Assist the CEO in preparing product roadmaps for business development efforts.
- Prepare Product Requirement Documents (PRDs) to translate the high-level requirement into the developer-friendly functional specification for each value-added feature.
- Responsible for communicating product progress with the internal development team, vendors, and various internal stakeholders weekly and monthly.
- Drive product management and development team for cross-platform applications
- Schedule tasks and monitor work completion weekly to ensure project milestones are delivered (2 weeks) each sprint.
- Delegate technical responsibilities and monitor the progress of the product.
- Conduct the development team recruitment process from preparing the job description to finalizing the candidate.

Product Owner

True Money Myanmar Co., Ltd.

March 2019 to Oct 2019

Job Responsibility

- Collaborate with Product Lead on technical feasibility while mentoring senior and junior developers & designers on technical, design, and UI/UX.
- Responsible for communicating project progress to clients and various internal stakeholders weekly.
- Collect the user experience survey and prepared the report with suggestions to revamp.

Project Manager

360ed Edu Tech Co., Ltd.

June 2018 to March 2019

Job Responsibility

- Assist CTO in preparing projects proposal for the business development effort.
- Drive project management for cross-platform support (Web, Android, iOS).
- Schedule tasks and monitor work completion weekly to ensure project milestones are delivered each sprint.

Program Manager

New Westminster Co., Ltd.

October 2016 to May 2018

Job Responsibility

- Report to CEO on requirement elicitation and market analysis for market research.
- Managed product roadmap through design and development processes web, Android & iOS: 1shotCV Job & CV Discovery Platform, and Kantgu Social Learning Platform.
- Responsible for estimation and task assignments to ensure target milestones are met.

Lead Developer

New Westminster Co., Ltd.

June 2015 to September 2016

Job Responsibility

- Translated clients' business needs into project requirements and specifications.
- Designed and implemented AJAX-enabled web applications using PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, and CSS in collaboration with graphic artists and web designers.
- Provide senior and junior developers with technical guidance.

Developer

Global Connect Asia

June 2013 – September 2014

Job Responsibility

- Developed web applications using PHP, JavaScript, MySQL as well as CMS frameworks.
- Developed Drupal CMS themes and templates according to design provided by UI/UX designer.

- Implemented event web apps by using the internal web form builder platform.
- Developed customized XML files to generate dynamic transactional web apps.

PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS

Htwet Toe (Agriculture)

Nov 2019 - Present

Htwet Toe, the product of Village Link, is an easy-to-use mobile-first platform that helps agricultural communities in Myanmar by providing professional advice, solutions, and services to increase yield and productivity. I was mainly responsible for vendor management when the platform was developed by a partner vendor's team before building the fully in-house team. Currently, I'm leading the development team which actively develops version 2.0 of the platform including web app, mobile, and content management dashboard.

Android : https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.awba.htwettoe

iOS : https://apps.apple.com/us/app/htwet-toe/id1568251272

Web Application: https://www.htwettoe.com

Zega Wallet App (Microfinance)

Oct 2022 - Present

Our partner company, Zega Finance, is providing financial services with different loan products in Myanmar. We are developing a digital platform supporting the service to purchase the load product and repayment called Aye Say Pay Wallet which is integrated with a core banking system for different platforms including iOS and Android.

Website: https://www.zegafinance.com

eKYC OCR - Pilot App (Microfinance)

Jul 2021 - Dec 2021

As another financial-related app, we developed the pilot application to collect customer information for Maha Microfinance, a leading financial service provider in the agricultural sector in Myanmar. The lead generation platform is designed to collect customer information for microfinance using OCR technology to scan the applicant's National Identity.

Web Application: https://maha-ekyc.htwettoe.com

OTHER PROJECTS

eCommerce - Mini Pilot App (Agriculture)

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

Customer Loyalty Platform

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

AI-Powered Pest and Diseases Detection – Mini Pilot App

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

AR/VR Applications (Education)

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

1Shot CV - CV Builder Platform/ Job Portal

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- Youth Entrepreneurship Program (2022 Mentor)
 - The program aims to remain an unpopular opinion among youth and business communities in secondary cities as many believe that it's a high-risk and uncertain approach to conducting business.
- I2N Challenge (2021 2nd Runner)
 - o Innovate to Nourish (I2N) Challenge is an MSMEs Challenge Activity from SBN Myanmar that aims to harness the power of innovations by working with SMEs.
- Product Talk (2021 **Organizer**)
 - o Organized the very first product community and event in early 2021.
- The Hackathon 2018, 2019 (Mentor)
 - o Mentored and supported the guideline for product development to fit the requirement of the hackathon.
- Agri Hack Challenge (2018 2nd Place)
 - Participated in Agriculture Hackathon organized by Myanma Awba and won 2nd place for the AR project.
- UNICEF Data Visualization Hackathon (2018 Organizer/ Mentor)
 - Mentored and provided project management guidance to the teams on how to scope and develop the project.
- Uni Hack Challenge Hackathon Series (1, 2 & 3 Organizer)
 - Responsible for organizing University Hackathon Challenge which is premier hackathon series with multiple themes (including blockchain) for Myanmar university students.